That is, if Moscow wants to
То есть если Москва захочет там
declare independence there and be within the
провозгласить независимость так и быть в
borders of the Urals, in principle,
границах до Урала в принципе вам в
it will make no difference to you in Siberia in the Trans-Baikal Territory.
Сибири в Забайкальском крае это будет
Personally, I’m honest. Personally, I’m just
так Лично мне честно Лично мне только
talking to myself; it makes absolutely no
говорю про себя мне абсолютно Без
difference.
разница
Hello Hello, I’m from the city of
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте я из города
Khmelnitsky
Хмельницкий Вы
Where am I from?  from the city of Chita, Chita,
откуда Я из города Чита Чита
Trans-Baikal Territory Wow, yes, very
Забайкальский край Ух ты да Да очень
interesting, yes, because the fact is that
интересно да потому что дело в том что
look, I’m an employee of an analytical
смотрите я работник аналитического
center for the
центра по
decentralization of the Federation, I’m conducting
децентрализация Федерации я вот провожу
research on how residents of the region
такие исследования как жители региона
perceive their economic,
воспринимают свои экономические
social and political ties with
социальные и политические связи с
other regions, so tell me how  have
другими регионами так вот скажите вы как
been to
часто бывали в
Moscow often, I’ve never been to Moscow, so
Москве я ни разу не была в Москве так
the question is, have you been to
вопрос а были ли вы в
China? I’ve never been to China, so I understand they were.
Китае ни разу не была в Китае так понял
does not interfere with surveys,
если нужно это такие не мешает опросам
see Which regions of the Russian
смотрите В каких регионах Российской
Federation have you
Федерации вы
been to? Irkutsk Region Khabarovsk Territory
были Иркутская область Хабаровский край
Trans-Baikal Territory That is, in fact,
Забайкальский край То есть фактически
everything that is within there is some kind of
всё что в пределах там какой-то да
approximation there within up to half a
приближающие там в пределах до полски
day’s drive, like yes, I understood absolutely correctly Yes,
суток езды типа да совершенно верно
look at the question too, yes we are
понял Да вот смотрите вопрос тоже да мы
studying  as far as
изучаем насколько
a man, please don’t blow
мужчина не дуйте пожалуйста в девушку
cigarette smoke at a girl, it’s not really pleasant for her.
сигаретным дымом ей это не совсем Может
Yes, look, we are
быть приятно Да вот смотрите мы мы
collecting information about these
собираем вот информацию о вот этих
social economic ties.
социальных экономических связях Как вы
Why do you think the residents of the Trans-Baikal
считаете почему жители Забайкальского
Territory do not go to
края не ездят в
Moscow? There is no money, but wait. This is what my brother
Москву денег нету а подождите Это брат
answered Now I  I’ll say Well, in the sense,
ответил Сейчас я скажу Ну в смысле
why doesn’t he go to Moscow? It’s
почему не едет в Москву это же Дело
everyone’s business, yes. Well, that’s why you
каждого вот да Ну вот почему вот вы
went to the nearby And you didn’t go to Moscow,
ездили в ближне А в Москву не ездили
like to the
вроде в
capital,
столицу
look, let’s say I have a
вот смотрите допустим у меня выпадает
vacation in the summer and I can choose any
отпуск летом и я могу выбрать любой
region of our
регион нашей
country, I have paid  tickets from
страны у меня оплачиваемые билеты от
work And I choose to go I want
работы И я выбираю поехать Я хочу
to go to St. Petersburg for example Well, I
поехать в санкт-петербург например Ну я
just don’t want to go to Moscow, I just went to
просто не хочу в Москву я ну просто
St. Petersburg No, I haven’t been, I just
Петербурге вы были Нет не была я просто
want to go there No, I honestly can’t answer you
хочу Нет я честно я вам не могу ответить
Although I know many people who are in
Хотя я знаю многих колле которые в
on vacation we went to Moscow, I really
отпуске съездили в Москву я правда вам
can’t even give you an adequate answer
не могу даже как-то адекватно ответить
to this question, why don’t people from Russia go there? Well,
на этот вопрос почему не ездят туда
it’s relatively
жителе России ну это это относительно
expensive, but it turns out to go to Moscow, but I ca
дорого да получается поехать в Москву а
n’t say that because it’s
я не могу этого сказать потому что
relatively expensive, why are tickets if Well,
относительно дорого чего билетов если Ну
relatively speaking.  your your possibilities
относительно Вот ваше ваших возможностей
Here you are, as a person who lives in the
Вот вы как человек который живёт в
Trans-Baikal Territory, I can’t say this
Забайкальском крае не могу этого сказать
because my work fully
потому что мне от работы полностью
pays for my travel there and back and, as
оплачивается проезд туда и обратно и как
if it were possible,
бы возможно
I can also afford a vacation. I
отдыха я тоже могу себе позволить Я
just, I just don’t want to go there. It turns out that
просто я просто не хочу туда получается
nothing binds you mentally.  with
вас ментально ничего не связывает с
Moscow,
Москвой
yes. And for example, Irkutsk, for example, with
да А например Иркутском например с
Khabarovsk. Why did you
Хабаровском Почему вы туда вот
go there? Well, these are friendly ties. I
ездили Ну это дружеские такие связи Мне
just needed to
просто нужно
share from another part of the Russian
было делиться от другой части Российской
Federation, for example, in the Urals, and to say
Федерации например по Уралу да сказать
that we don’t need this
что вот нам не нужно вот этот
Trans-Baikal Territory, for example,
Забайкальский край например
Primorsky Territory, the Urals, all of Siberia  Yes,
Приморский край Урал весь Сибирь Да вот
we want to be the European part of Russia
мы хотим быть европейской частью России
up to the Urals, you won’t be
до Урала вы не будете
against it, not absolutely parallel, I understand that
против не абсолютно параллельно понял то
is, if Moscow wants to
есть если Москва захочет там
declare independence there and be within the
провозгласить независимость так и быть в
borders up to the Urals, in principle, for you in
границах до Урала в принципе вам в
Siberia in the Trans-Baikal Territory it will make
Сибири в Забайкальском крае это будет
no difference so Personally, honestly
без разницы так
Personally  I’m just talking
Лично мне честно Лично мне только говорю
to myself, I absolutely don’t care, I understand, yes,
про себя мне абсолютно без разницы понял
but look at this question
Понял да А вот смотрите ещё такой вопрос
: what is Moscow now giving to your region and what is
что Москва сейчас даёт вашему региону и
your region giving to Moscow? As I understand it, your Moscow is taking
что ваш регион даёт Москве я так понимаю
money, resources
ваш Москва забирает у вас деньги ресурсы
and people from you. So, for example, what does Moscow give to
и людей Так а что например Москва даёт
your regions?  in the Trans-Baikal Territory,
вашим регионам вот Забайкальскому краю
for example.
например
Probably money and people are wrong. Moscow is not
Наверно деньги и людей не так Моск не
Moscow, it’s taking money and resources and
Москва же забирает деньги и ресурсы и
people
людей
and money, I think so because we
и деньги я так думаю потому что у нас
have a lot of
есть очень много
companies,
компаний всё
damn it, like it. So that means we’ve
блин лайк Так значит мы немножко
changed our tactics a little, we’re asking now. Yes,
поменяли тактику мы теперь спрашиваем Да
not just as if  someone will separate there
не просто как если там кто-то отделится
And now if Moscow separates from you,
А теперь если Москва отделится от вас
will you be against it, no, that is, this is
будете ли вы против нет то есть вот это
what we always tell Yes, people don’t
то что мы всегда рассказываем Да людям
give a damn about Moscow, yes Moscow perceives
насрать на Москву да Москва воспринимает
some kind of parasite that only
какой-то такой паразит который только
eats the juices from different regions Yes, if
жрёт соки с разных регионов Да если
Moscow will  there to announce independence
Москва будет там огласить независимость
everything she says She doesn’t care
всё она говорит Ей пофиг
so they live in their own little
так они живут вот в своём каком-то там
world Yes she went to the nearest regions
мирке Да она в ближайшие регионы ездила
Moscow for her it’s something you know Why the
Москва для неё это что-то такое знаешь
hell should she go there so nothing
вот Нахрена туда ехать так ничего её не
connects her with Moscow she’s not a great Russian
связывает с Москвой не великая русская
culture  doesn’t want to go to St. Petersburg, in
культура она не хочет походить в Питере
short, well, I wanted to Yes, but for some reason I didn’t go
короче ну хотела Да но не поехала
Yes, this is all this is a different world,
почему-то Да вот это всё это другой мир
subscribe to th Telegram right away,
подпишись на й Telegram прям зараз овин
but
а
for now it’s even more and more
пок це дуже и дуже
polite
важливо